Finding Aid for John Engler Papers, 1968-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Gubernatorial Papers, 1970-2003; 411 linear feet
  - Communications Division, 1991-2002; 99 linear feet
    - Speechwriter John Nevin, 1991-2002; 10.3 linear feet
      - Department of Mental Health (DMH)/Dodak Lawsuit/Lafayette Clinic, 1992 (Box 76)
      - DMH Violence Prevention Paper, 1994 (Box 76)
      - Department of Natural Resources (DNR) Accomplishments, 1994 (Box 76)
      - DNR Reorganization, undated (Box 76)
      - Detroit, 1993-1997 (Box 76)
      - Detroit College of Law, 1998 (Box 76)
      - Detroit/DNR Park concept, 1994 (Box 76)
      - Detroit Economic Club Speech, 1994-1996 (Box 76)
      - Detroit/Environmental Policy, 1995 (Box 76)
      - Detroit Free Press re: Negative Engler Reporting, 1991 (Box 76)
      - Detroit/Money from State, 1995-1996 (Box 76)
      - Detroit/Renaissance Zones, 1995 (Box 76)
      - Detroit Report, 1998 (Box 76)
      - Development of Platform for 1998 Election, 1994-1998, 1 folders (Box 76)
      - Development of Platform for 1998 Election, 1994-1998 (cont.), 4 folders (Box 77)
      - DeVos, Richard, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Dickman, Murray, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Disabilities, 1994 (Box 77)
      - Dole, Bob and Elizabeth, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Dole, Bob/Abortion, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Dole, Bob/Agriculture, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Dole, Bob/Briefing, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Dole, Bob/Memo, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Dole, Bob/Speeches, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Dole, Bob/Tax Cut, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Domestic violence, 1991; 1994; 2 folders (Box 77)
      - Dresch, Representative Stephen P.,1991 (Box 77)
      - Driver Savings and Lawsuit Protection, 1997 (Box 77)
      - Drug Dealer Liability Act, 1994 (Box 77)
      - Durant Case, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Earned income credit, 1994 (Box 77)
      - East Lansing Kiwanis Club, 1995-1996 (Box 77)
      - Eaton, Robert/Chrysler, 1995-1996 (Box 77)
      - Economic Impacts of Casino Gaming on the State of Michigan, undated (Box 77)
        (Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu International)
      - Economic News and G-7 conference, 1994 (Box 77)
      - Economic Overview, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Economy, 1990 (Box 77)
      - Editor's Day in Lansing, 1991; 2 folders (Box 77)
      - Education/Accountability, 1996-1997 (Box 77)
      - Education/America, 2000; 1991 (Box 77)
      - Education/Career Scholarship Announcement, 1998 (Box 77)
      - Education/Department of Education, 1997 (Box 77)
      - Education/Detroit, 1998-1999 (Box 77)
      - Education/Funding, 1991 (Box 77)
      - Education Reform Database, 1995 (Box 77)
      - Education Segment Speech at Republican National Convention, 1996 (Box 77)
      - Elections/Ballot Issues, 1996 (Box 77)
      - E-mail messages to John M. Engler, 1994 (Box 77)
      - Emergency Needs AFDC, 1991 (Box 78)
      - Emissions Trading/Background for Staff, 1993; 2 folders (Box 78)
      - End of Life, 1999 (Box 78)
      - Engler, John
        - Accomplishments
          - Corrections, 1998 (Box 78)
          - General, 2002 (Box 78)
          - Graphs, 2002 (Box 78)
          - Headlines, 2002 (Box 78)
          - Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 78)
          - Print Media
            - Education, 1995-2001 (Box 78)
            - Environmental Quality, 1996-2001 (Box 78)
            - History, Arts & Libraries, 1997-2002 (Box 78)
            - Natural Resources, 1994-2002 (Box 78)
          - Quotes, 2002 (Box 78)
        - Action Agenda, 1996 (Box 78)
        - Book jacket quote for Bob Peterson's Drug Enforcement Works, 1997 (Box 78)
        - Book jacket quote for Dan Angel's Managing Back, 1995 (Box 78)
        - Editorials (Detroit Free Press), 1991-1997 (Box 78)
        - Editorials (New York Times), 1991 (Box 78)
        - Editorials (Wall Street Journal), 1991 (Box 78)
        - Introduction, 1990-1997 (Box 78)
        - Negative Press, 1991-1995; 2 folders (Box 78)
        - Testimony/Reforming the Present Welfare System, US House of Representatives, 1995 (Box 78)
        - Votes, 1996 (Box 78)
      - Engineering (Michigan Jobs Commission), undated (Box 78)
      - Environment/Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), 1993 (Box 78)
      - Environment/President Bush, 1992 (Box 78)
      - Environmental Achievement Ideas, 1993 (Box 78)
      - Environmental Issues, 1995-1997 (Box 78)
      - Environmental Quality, 1995-1998 (Box 78)
      - Environmental Regulatory Burden, 1996 (Box 78)
      - Environmental Strategy, 1996 (Box 78)
      - Establishing the Governor as One of a Kind, 1993 (Box 78)
      - Ethanol Coalition Meeting report, JME letter to Clinton, 1993 (Box 78)
      - Executive Authority, 1995 (Box 78)
      - Executive Budget FY, 1996 (Box 78)
      - Exports, 1994-1995 (Box 78)
      - Family Independence Agency Report (To Strengthen Michigan Families), 1996 (Box 78)
      - Farm Issues, 1996 (Box 78)
      - Fatherhood Project, 1996 (Box 78)
      - Filing President George Bush's affidavit of candidacy, 1992 (Box 78)
      - Fire safety/Michigan Task Force, 1991 (Box 78)
      - Fisher, Max, 1995-1996 (Box 78)
      - Flat tax, 1995 (Box 78)
      - Food Stamps/Fraud, 1991 (Box 79)
      - Forbes Point-of-View Article, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Ford, President Gerald (Box 79)
      - Forest Products, undated (Box 79)
      - Fuller, Howard, 1995 (Box 79)
        (Prof. of Education at Marquette University, Ex-superintendent of Milwaukee School System)
      - Gays in the military, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Gay marriage information, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Genetic privacy, 1997 (Box 79)
      - GMI lecture notes, 1996 (Box 79)
        (Nevin's lecture about speechwriting, "How you present your ideas is almost as important as the ideas themselves.)
      - GOPAC Teleconference Training School, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Governor Engler's Accomplishments in Downsizing and Privatization, 1995 (Box 79)
      - Governors' Apple Wager, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Governor's Arts Awards, 1991-1994 (Box 79)
      - Governor's Blue Ribbon Commission on Michigan Gaming, 1995 (Box 79)
      - Governor's Football League, 1996 (Box 79)
        (Office football pool)
      - Governor's Office/Legislative Liaison Pig Roast, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Great Lakes, 1994-1995 (Box 79)
      - Great Lakes Pollution Prevention, 1991 (Box 79)
      - Great Lakes Protection Fund, 1991-1995 (Box 79)
      - Greyhounds, 1995-1999 (Box 79)
      - Habitat for Humanity, 1997 (Box 79)
      - Handbook of Public Policy Evaluation/Stuart Nagel, 2001 (Box 79)
      - Hannah Report, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Harvard School of Education, 1995 (Box 79)
      - Haveman, Jim, 1992; 1997; 2 folders (Box 79)
        (Director of the Department of Community Health)
      - Hayes, Robin, 1996 (Box 79)
        (Republican candidate for Governor in North Carolina)
      - Headlee Report, 1994 (Box 79)
      - Head Start, 1991 (Box 79)
      - Health Care Reform, 1993 (Box 79)
      - Health Care/State of Michigan (Box 79)
      - Health Insurance, 1994 (Box 79)
      - Heintz, Suzy, 1996 (Box 79)
        (Michigan Republican Party Chair)
      - Henry Ford Academy, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Herald-Palladium Editorial Board, 1998 (Box 79)
      - Heritage Foundation, 1989-1999; 3 folders (Box 79)
      - Hillegonds, Paul, 1996 (Box 79)
        (Speaker of the Michigan House of Representatives)
      - Hills, Rusty/Memos, 1997-1998 (Box 79)
      - Historic Nixon materials, copies of materials from, 1950s (Box 79)
      - Holocaust remembrance, 1995-1997 (Box 79)
      - Homeless initiatives/Statistics, 1991 (Box 79)
      - Homelessness/Shanty campaign, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Homework Hotline, 1991 (Box 79)
      - Humphrey, Carl, 1992 (Box 79)
        (Homeless activist)
      - Iacocca, Lee/Remarks, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Intelligent Transportation Society Detroit Meeting, 1998 (Box 79)
      - Interstate Sales Tax, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Invitations to Governor, 1990-1991 (Box 79)
      - Japan-American Auto Agreement, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Japan International Trade, 1991 (Box 79)
      - Japan-Michigan relations, 1993 (Box 79)
      - Jason Project, 1999 (Box 79)
      - Jewish National Federation/Tree of Life Award, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Job Training Partnership Act Areas, 1992 (Box 79)
      - Jobs Commission, undated (Box 79)
        (Promotional materials)
      - Jobs Commission, 1997 (Box 80)
      - Jobs Commission Report, 1993 (Box 80)
      - Journalism/Ethics, 1995-1997 (Box 80)
      - Jokes, undated (Box 80)
      - Journalism/Ethics, 1995-1997 (Box 80)
      - Judicial Appointment, 1996-1999 (Box 80)
      - Justice/Police, 1995 (Box 80)
      - Justice in Michigan, 1995 (Box 80)
      - Kemp, Jack, 1996 (Box 80)
        (Bob Dole's Vice Presidential running mate)
      - Kent County Rap-Tab Column, 1991 (Box 80)
      - Kevorkian Information, 1996 (Box 80)
        (Dr. Jack Kevorkian)
      - Kids Hope USA, 1996 (Box 80)
      - Kirk, Russell/Heritage Lectures, 1986-1991 (Box 80)
        (Leading conservative thinker)
      - Lake Orion/Charter Schools, 1995 (Box 80)
      - Letters to the Editor, 1991 (Box 80)
      - Letters to the Editor, 1998 (Box 80)
      - Leesburg, 1995 (Box 80)
      - Life Sciences Corridor, 2001 (Box 80)
      - Ludington Pumped Storage Plant Settlement, undated (Box 80)
        (contains sample of netting and photographs)
      - Mackinac Book, Vol. II, 1996 (Box 80)
      - Mackinac Center for Public Policy, 1988-1997; 3 folders (Box 80)
      - Mackinac Conference, 1991 (Box 80)
      - Mackinac Detroit Chamber of Commerce, 1996 (Box 80)
      - Macomb Economic Club, 1996 (Box 80)
      - Mapping Arts and Cultural Funding in Michigan, 1997 (Box 80)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Innovation Summit, 1998 (Box 80)
      - Matalin, Mary, 1992 (Box 80)
      - Mawby, Russell, 1997 (Box 80)
      - McManus, George, undated (Box 80)
      - Medicaid/National Governors' Association, 1996 (Box 80)
      - Medicare, 1995-1996 (Box 80)
      - MEAP, 1999 (Box 80)
      - Mehan, Tracy, 1995-1997; 2 folders (Box 80)
        (Office of the Great Lakes)
      - Memos from Rusty Hills, undated (Box 80)
      - Mental Health Statistics/Lafayette Clinic, 1994 (Box 80)
      - Mercury Information, 1995-1996 (Box 80)
      - MetroParent/Explaining Rodney King verdict, 1992 (Box 80)
      - MI Future: Crossing to the New Economy, undated (Box 80)
      - Michigan Association of Broadcasters, 1998-1999 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Association of Counties, 1997 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Association of School Boards, 1995 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Auto Dealers Association, 1997 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Brownfield Redevelopment Program, 1998-1999 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Department of Corrections (M-DOC) media advisory, 1993 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Department of Mental Health Report (MI-DMH), 1994 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Department of Transportation (MDOT) Budget FY, 1997 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Economic Growth Authority (MEGA) Wall Street Journal, 1995 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Economic Outlook, 1998 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Economic Profile, Mark Haas, 1990 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Employment Security Commission, 1992 (Box 80)
      - Michigan Environment at Risk, 1992 (Box 80)
      - Michigan History, 1998 (Box 80)
      - Michigan House of Representatives, 1991 (Box 80)
      - Michigan House Republicans, 1996 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Lottery/Annual Report, 1991 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Lottery/Letter to the Editor, 1992 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Merit Award, 1999 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Millennium Initiative, undated (Box 81)
      - Michigan Neighborhood Partnership, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Personal Income Estimate, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Personal Income Report, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Press Association Winter Convention, 1992 (Box 81)
      - Michigan resident's quotes, 1993 (Box 81)
      - Michigan small business survey/Health care, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Michigan State Bar, 1995 (Box 81)
      - Michigan State Housing Development Authority (MSHDA), 1994 (Box 81)
      - MSHDA Letter on Mortgage Bonds, 1991 (Box 81)
      - Michigan State University (MSU) Football, 1996 (Box 81)
      - Michigan: Still the Automotive State?, 1992 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Task Force on Violence Prevention and Reduction, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Michigan Women's Commission Essay Contest, 1993 (Box 81)
      - Michigan's Courts in the 21st Century, 1990 (Box 81)
      - Michigan's Individual Income Tax, 1992 (Box 81)
      - Michigan's Individual Income Tax, 1996 (Box 81)
      - Minivan Tariff, 1992-1996 (Box 81)
      - Minority Vendors, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Miscellaneous, 1991-1999; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - More, Sir Thomas, 1999 (Box 81)
      - Mormon Welfare Plan, undated (Box 81)
      - Mothers' Day Proclamation, 1991 (Box 81)
      - Municipal League, 1997 (Box 81)
      - Municipal League Info, 1997 (Box 81)
      - Murphy Event, 1996 (Box 81)
        (Judge William B. Murphy)
      - National Association of Business Economists (NABE), 1997 (Box 81)
      - National Environmental Policy Institute, 1999 (Box 81)
      - National Forum Water Report, undated (Box 81)
      - National Governors' Association
        - Survey of the states, 1991 (Box 81)
        - Summer meeting, 1992 (Box 81)
        - Winter meeting, 1994 (Box 81)
        - Summer meeting, 1998 (Box 81)
      - National Speechwriters' Clinic, 1994 (Box 81)
      - National Tax Limitation Committee, 1991 (Box 81)
      - Needle Program/AIDS, 1996 (Box 81)
      - Neighborhood Enterprise Zones, 1991 (Box 81)
      - New Partnerships: The Power of Voluntary Citizen Service, undated (Box 81)
      - New York Times/Tax Letter, 1992 (Box 81)
      - Newcomen Society, 1996 (Box 81)
      - News Clips from JME's office to writers, 1991 (Box 81)
      - Notes from the Governor to Speechwriters, 1991-1999; 3 folders (Box 81)
      - Notes from the Governor to Speechwriters (cont.), 1991-1999; 6 folders (Box 82)
      - Notes from Tracey Mehan (Office of the Great Lakes) (Box 82)
      - Nunn, Jon, 1995 (Box 82)
        (Michigan's National Republican Committeeman, roast)
      - Oakland Community College, 1997 (Box 82)
      - Olmstead, David, 1997 (Box 82)
      - Ontario, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Op Eds, 1991 (Box 82)
      - Open Door, 1991; 2 folders (Box 82)
      - Organization for International Investment, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Our Kids Deserve Better, 1993 (Box 82)
      - Owen Poll, 1997 (Box 82)
      - Partnership for New Education, 1991 (Box 82)
        (Includes by-laws)
      - Patterson, Brooks, 1992 (Box 82)
      - Pero, Colleen/Letter to the Editor of State News, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Pero, Dan, undated (Box 82)
        (Chief of Staff)
      - Peterson, Peter/Economic Outlook, 1993 (Box 82)
      - Petoskey-Harbor Springs Chamber of Commerce, 1991 (Box 82)
      - Policy and Procedures/Communications Division, 1991 (Box 82)
      - Pork Barrel Awards, 1989-1990 (Box 82)
      - Pollution prevention, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Prayer Breakfast, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Press clip survey of state departments, undated (Box 82)
      - Prison Litigation Reform, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Privatization, 1992 (Box 82)
      - Privatization info, 1994 (Box 82)
      - Pro-Life Candidate Material, 1993 (Box 82)
      - Proposal A Success, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Public Relations Association of Michigan (PRAM)/Nevin Speech on Insults, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Public School Academies, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Quotations, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Raciot: Lincoln Day Dinner, 1993 (Box 82)
      - Reapportionment, 1991 (Box 82)
      - Redevelopment of Detroit Plan, G. Wolfram, 1993 (Box 82)
      - Reducing the Size and Cost of Government/Evergreen Freedom Foundation, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Relative Environmental Risk Material/Upper Peninsula, 1992 (Box 82)
      - Renaissance Plan, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Renaissance Zones, 1996-1998 (Box 82)
      - Republican Governors' Association (RGA)
        - Book, 1996 (Box 82)
        - Economic Summit, 1996 (Box 82)
        - Innovative Solutions for America (Michigan on p. 31) (Box 82)
        - New Hampshire candidate Ovide Lamontagne, 1996 (Box 82)
        - News, 1996-1997 (Box 82)
        - Pfizer report, 1997 (Box 82)
        - Republican Ideas in Action, 1996 (Box 82)
        - Summit participant biographies, 1996 (Box 82)
        - Talking points on Clinton Budget, 1993 (Box 82)
      - Republican National Convention (RNC) (Box 83)
        - Democratic Welfare Reform Plan, 1995 (Box 83)
        - Detroit, 1997 (Box 83)
        - Education Segment background, 1996 (Box 83)
        - Info, 1996 (Box 83)
        - Scripts, 1996 (Box 83)
        - Speech Drafts, 1996 (Box 83)
      - Republican Platform, 1996 (Box 83)
      - Republican State Convention, 1996 (Box 83)
      - Restoring Entrepreneurial Michigan, 1992 (Box 83)
      - Reuss, Lloyd, 1995 (Box 83)
        (Executive Dean of Focus Hope)
      - Revenue sharing, 1997 (Box 83)
      - Revenue sharing and road funding, ca., 1997 (Box 83)
      - Revitalization of Animal Agriculture in Michigan, undated (Box 83)
      - Reynolds, Nanette/Speech ideas, 1994 (Box 83)
      - Riegle, Don, 1992 (Box 83)
      - Right-to-Life, 1998-2002 (Box 83)
      - Right-to-Life ads, 1996 (Box 83)
      - Right-to-Life (Henry Hyde), 1987; 1991 (Box 83)
      - Roads, 1998 (Box 83)
      - Romney, George (Box 83)
      - Romney, George/Historic Newspaper Issues, 1962-1995 (Box 83)
      - Romney, George/State of the State Speeches, 1963-1969 (Box 83)
      - Romney, George/Volunteer, undated (Box 83)
      - Ryan prisoner escapes report, 1994 (Box 83)
      - Sainte Anne de Detroit, 1999 (Box 83)
      - Salvation Army, 1992 (Box 83)
      - Schaub, Emilia, 1991 (Box 83)
      - School Choice, 1999 (Box 83)
      - School Choice/Friedman Foundation, 1997 (Box 83)
      - School Funding, 1997 (Box 83)
      - Secchia Commission, 1994 (Box 83)
      - Secchia Commission Report, 1995 (Box 83)
      - Second Inaugural Address, 1995 (Box 83)
      - Senior Staff Retreat, 2001 (Box 83)
      - Service Delivery Area (SDA) Target GA's, 1991 (Box 83)
      - Shadow Cabinet, 1996 (Box 83)
        (Bob Dole)
      - Single Business Tax, 1995-1997 (Box 83)
      - Social Services, Department of (Michigan), 1992 (Box 83)
      - Southeast Michigan Council of Governments
        - Ozone Reduction Plan, 1994 (Box 83)
        - Transportation Improvement Plan, 1997 (Box 83)
      - Speech Assignments, 1999-2000 (Box 83)
      - Speech ideas, quips, 1995 (Box 83)
      - Spoils system rough draft, undated (Box 83)
      - Staffing the Governor, 1994 (Box 83)
      - State Assistance for Water, 1991 (Box 83)
      - State Cabinets breakdown (minorities), undated (Box 83)
      - State of the Judiciary, 1997 (Box 83)
      - State of the State, 1991-1992; 1996; 6 folders (Box 83)
      - State of the State, 1997 (Box 84)
        - Accomplishments (Box 84)
        - Adoption (Box 84)
        - Balanced Budget Amendments (Box 84)
        - Black Veterans (Box 84)
        - Budget (Box 84)
        - Cabinet (Box 84)
        - Drafts, 2 folders (Box 84)
        - Ideas (Box 84)
        - Monroe (Box 84)
        - National Resources Stewardship (Box 84)
        - Notes (Box 84)
        - Other States State of the State (Box 84)
        - State of the State, 1997 (Box 84)
        - Taxes/Jobs (Box 84)
        - Technology (Box 84)
        - Transportation (Box 84)
        - Welfare/Children (Box 84)
      - State of the State, 1998-1999; 2001; 4 folders (Box 84)
      - State of the Union, 1991 (Box 84)
      - Stephens, Ret. Col. William J., undated (Box 84)
      - Summit Agenda, 1997 (Box 84)
        (President's Summit for America's Future)
      - Sylvan "Results '97" Conference background material, 1997 (Box 84)
      - Talking points, 1995; undated; 2 folders (Box 84)
      - Task Force on the Acquisitions of Contractual Personal Services, 1991 (Box 84)
      - Tax cut information, 1996 (Box 84)
      - Tax Freedom Day, 1996 (Box 84)
      - Tax policy, 1996 (Box 84)
      - Tax Research Analysis Center (TRAC)
        - The 1993 Michigan Fiscal Reforms, 1997, 1993-1997 (Box 84)
        - School Vouchers, 1997 (Box 84)
          (Annotated by Engler)
      - Timber Producers Association, 1991 (Box 84)
      - Tobacco, 1994 (Box 84)
      - To Strengthen Michigan Families, 1995 (Box 84)
      - Transportation/Federal funding, 1997 (Box 84)
      - Travel Bureau, 1991 (Box 84)
      - Tribal tax, 2002 (Box 84)
      - Trucks/Weight limits, 1998 (Box 84)
      - Unfunded federal mandates, 1994 (Box 84)
      - United Way/Benton Harbor, 1997 (Box 84)
      - University of Michigan Breakfast, 1997 (Box 84)
      - Urban agenda, 1993-1995 (Box 84)
      - Urban initiative, 1998 (Box 84)
      - Urban strategy, 1995 (Box 84)
      - Veto messages, 1992 (Box 84)
      - Victory '96 Plan, undated (Box 85)
      - Victory line, 1992 (Box 85)
      - Vital Speeches, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Volunteer Summit, 1997; 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Washington Times Letter/Douglas Roberts, 1997 (Box 85)
      - Welfare, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Welfare (Anti-Clinton), 1996 (Box 85)
      - Welfare Reform, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Welfare Reform/Chronology, 1997 (Box 85)
      - Welfare Reform/To Strengthen Michigan's Families (Box 85)
      - Western Michigan University Commencement, 1991 (Box 85)
        (Engler received honorary degree.)
      - Wetlands, 1991 (Box 85)
      - White House, 1991-1992; 5 folders (Box 85)
        (Copies of President Bush's speeches)
      - White House/America 2000 Education Strategy, 1991, 1991-2000 (Box 85)
      - White House/Rhetoric, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Whitewater: Talking Points, 1994 (Box 85)
      - Williamsburg Resolve, 1994 (Box 85)
        (Republican Governors' Association)
      - Winter Cities Forum, Marquette, 1997 (Box 85)
      - Women for Dole information, 1996 (Box 85)
      - Woodworth, Patti, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Work First, 1994 (Box 85)
        (Welfare Reform)
      - Workforce, 1994 (Box 85)
      - Workforce Development, 1997 (Box 85)
      - Worker Right to Know Act, 1996 (Box 85)
    - Newspapers and Magazines, 1970-2002; 0.5 linear feet
      The fourth subseries, "Newspapers and Magazines," holds articles either by or about Engler, including several magazines which feature him on the cover. In 1996, Engler was considered a strong candidate for Robert Dole's running mate, and the articles in the national press that year discuss his viability as a candidate.
      - AdCrafters, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Ad-Vision (Beulah, Michigan), 1998 (Box 85)
      - American Spectator, 1995 (Box 85)
      - Ann Arbor Regional Business to Business, 1996 (Box 85)
      - Arab American News, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Arab American Political Action Committee, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Boston Globe, 1996 (Box 85)
      - Business Monthly, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Business Week, 1996 (Box 85)
      - CEI Update, 1996 (Box 85)
      - City and State, 2000; 1992 (Box 85)
      - Corporate Detroit, 1994 (Box 85)
      - Crains Detroit Business, 1992-1997 (Box 85)
      - Detroit Free Press, 1994-2002 (Box 85)
      - Detroit News, 1994-1999 (Box 85)
      - Detroit News/Free Press USA Weekend, 1996 (Box 85)
      - Economist, 1996 (Box 85)
      - El Hispano News, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Enterprise (Michigan Manuf. Assoc.), 1992-1998 (Box 85)
      - FG Consulting, undated (Box 85)
      - Flinstonian Times, 1997-1998 (Box 85)
      - GQ, 1996 (Box 85)
      - Governing, 2001 (Box 85)
      - Grand Rapids Press, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Great Lakes Cruiser, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Great Lakes Sport Fishing News, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Great Lakes Business Monthly, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Investors Business Daily, 1997 (Box 85)
      - Jackson Business, 1994 (Box 85)
      - Jewish News, 1991 (Box 85)